



brianbancroft

"I am a Junior Developer with a passion for clean code, learning new concepts, data-mining, front-end development and process-automation. Before switiching to development, I worked long and hard in the Communications Branch of the Military, followed by the Geospatial Industry. My education background was in Physics and GIS. I seek to grow as a developer so that I can become a specialist in GIS Development. On my own, I draw, teach, read essays, write articles, and go on long hikes."

## PORTFOLIO - BRIANBANCROFT.CA

Examples of projects available at brianbancroft.ca include:

Trivia Collector - Backend Get my MP - Backend Condobees - Fullstack Map Georeferencing - Scripting

RAILS JQUERY RAILS A **CHARTS** 

## **EXPERIENCE**

May 2016 -Present

Web Developer, What to Do Company (w2d.co)

Full-Stack Production Web Development

- · Development for client websites using a stack which includes Ruby on Rails (4/5), Vue.JS, PostGIS, PostGres, Vanilla JS, SASS, Pug
- · Deployment of site onto Ubuntu Server using Webpack
- · Creation and consumption of Web APIs

Oct 2014 -Mar 2016

Field Technician, Integrity Technologies

- Field-based mapping, analysis and radio management · Created daily-changing operational maps for oil exploration.
- · Worked alone to maintain and troubleshoot to a large radio network used by field operators in a Winter Drilling or emergency response environment
- · Tracked, monitored and carried out analysis on individuals using a real-time GPS position feed provided from the above radios

Library Technician, University of Ottawa, Geographical Statistical and Government Center

Jan 2014 -May 2014

Front-end client service and support for library users, special projects in support of subject librarians

- Automation of large-scale georeferencing and file preparation for online distribution using Python
- · Assistance with students and university staff in seeking and acquiring data through multiple sources

Geophysicist's Assistant, Natural Resources Canada (FSWEP)

Nov 2012 -Sept 2013

Carrying out research and field tasks under direct supervision of a Geophysicst researcher

- · Magneteotelluric modelling, writing results and providing advice based on results
- Drafting and submitting results successfully through a peer-review process (Open File 7549)

## **EDUCATION**

Hon B.Sc, Double Major (Physics, Geomatics)

University of Ottawa

Sept 2009 -Dec 2013

Cartography, Databases, Linear Algebra, Multivariable Calculus, Differentials, Particle Mechanics, Waves and Optics, Electrodynamics, Thermodynamics, Geomorphology, Natural Resource Management, Impact Assessments, Geospatial Problem-Solving

## CERTIFICATION, AWARDS

Chief Scout's Award, 1999 Canadian Forces Decoration, 2013 ESRI Certification - Desktop Associate, 2016